$Phone: +32\ 491\ 43\ 88\ 90$  email: alexandros.dermenakis@gmail.com

#### RESUME

Over the years I have acquired experience working in both technical and managerial positions. I have been guiding technically and architecturally teams of 4 to 16 developers in both new and existing projects. Some of my most notable projects were the technical planning and guidance to bring large in-house databases to the Azure Cloud (General Mills) and being the architect on the DAM upgrade of Hilton on Azure. Furthermore, I have been providing technical support for integrations to big customers such as General Motors and guiding on Cloud Development. Apart from the private sector, I have also worked on government projects. My experience is with the Belgian government where I was responsible for undertaking the implementation of a traffic control system, consisting of a web and a mobile application.

#### SKILLS

Operational: SCRUM, Agile, RUP, Kanban, Coaching & Training, Release management.

Support, Recruitment, Team Management, Conflict Management

**Technical:** Azure Cloud, Power BI, Version Control, Software development, Automated deployments

# **EXPERIENCE**

Technical Support Team Manager

January 2019 - Present

Sitecore, Vorst, Belgium

- On-boarding and guidance of the global support team
- Task distribution and follow up with support team
- Define support process and automation of day to day tasks
- Owner of Cloud Development training of the Sitecore's DAM
- Assisting partners & customers with architectural decisions and integrations

Solutions Architect

August 2017 - December 2018

Sitecore, Vorst, Belgium

- Driving projects technically and communicating with clients
- Proof of concepts and pre-sales work using cloud technologies
- Software development with javascript, C# and Elastic Search
- Azure Cloud
- Data modeling and reporting with Power BI
- Preparation and execution of training to customers & partners
- Support and architectural studies for integrations teams (Web applications, Azure function & Logic Apps)

Software Project Manager

September 2014 - July 2017

TEIN Technology, Schaerbeek, Belgium

- Budget Control & Planning
- Technical documentation & requirements analysis
- Driving software development & automation projects (Agile & SCRUM)
- Pre-sales work for tenders (Private & Government)
- Resource management & Leadership (Internal & Outsourced teams)

Software Engineer

October 2013 - August 2014

TEIN Technology, Schaerbeek, Belgium

- Customization of Embedded Linux distributions
- VoIP and Linux programming in C++
- Developed with Qt 5 and QML an Embedded HMI interface
- Requirements gathering and project planning

Software Engineer

September 2012 - August 2013

ArKaos SA, Rhode-Saint-Genese, Belgium

- Project planning and requirements gathering
- Meeting with distributors worldwide for improvement of products
- Programming in C++ for Mac OS X and Windows

Software Engineer

June 2012 - September 2012

Nokia Norge AS, Oslo, Norway

- Worked on Qt Core with C/C++
- Designed and implemented a Qt patch for Color Profiles

Embedded Systems Software Engineer (Freelancer) February 2011 - September 2012 Terragon Environmental Technologies Inc., Montreal, QC, Canada

- Real-time OS development based on Linux (C & C++)
- Development using Qt and QML

Web Developer/Designer

May 2010 - July 2010

ZabAdoo Ltd., Athens, Greece

- Communicated with clients
  - Designed and maintained websites
  - Worked on company's CMS

Software Engineer

May 2009 - August 2009

Dassault Systmes, Montreal, QC, Canada

- Designed & Developed plug-ins for CATIA using C++
- Worked with Human modeling and Simulation algorithms

Software Developer

September 2008 - December 2008

Matrox Electronic Systems, Dorval, QC, Canada

- Developed and debugged drivers on Mac OS X
- Designed & Developed a video playback library
- Created video effects using OpenGL and QuickTime

CERTIFICATIONS

PRINCE2 Foundation, PRINCE2 Practitioner

LANGUAGES

• English (fluent) French (fluent)

• Greek (fluent) Swedish (beginner)

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Master in Management (part-time) Vrije Universiteit Brussel, Brussels, Belgium

2015 - 2018

Master of Science, Embedded Systems (part-time) Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

2011 - 2014

• Thesis at Nokia Norway on Color Profiles for Embedded Devices

Bachelor of Engineering, Software Engineering Concordia University, Monteal, QC, Canada

2006 - 2011

• Member of the Institute for Co-operative Education

# DISTINCTIONS

- Co-operative Education internships passed with distinction
- Dean's list for last academic year of bachelor's (annual GPA 4.16/4.30)

# ACADEMIC

Lab Assistant in Computer Architecture Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

April 2012 - May 2012

- Explained MIPS assembly to students
- Helped solving assignments

Teacher's Assistant in Discrete Mathematics Concordia University, Montreal, QC, Canada September 2008 - December 2008

- Wrote questions for tutorial sessions and corrected in class exercises
- Solved problems on the board for students
- Provided the students with my personal notes

### RESEARCH

Computer Architecture and Power Efficiency Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

January 2012 - September 2012

- Measuring power consumption on CPUs
- Creation of model according to application characteristics
- Construction of hardware for measuring power consumption

**PUBLICATIONS** A Novel Approach to Color Conversion on Embedded Devices

2013

Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden Thesis work related to highly optimized color conversion for Embedded Systems using OpenGL ES 2 for performing color conversion through pixel shaders.